If you can't get out, get even.
The Longest Yard is a drama, comedy, crime film directed by Peter Segal.
Disgraced pro football quarterback Paul Crewe lands in a Texas federal penitentiary, where manipulative
Warden Hazen recruits him to advise the institution's football team of prison guards.
Crewe suggests a tune-up game which lands him quarterbacking a
crew of inmates in a game against the guards.
Aided by incarcerated ex-NFL coach and player Nate Scarborough, Crewe and his team must overcome not only the
bloodthirstiness of the opposition, but also the corrupt warden trying to fix the game against them.
Paul Crewe, played by Adam Sandler.
Caretaker, played by Chris Rock.
Warden Hazen, played by James Cromwell.
Coach Nate Scarborough, played by Burt Reynolds.
Megget, played by Nelly.
Cheeseburger Eddy, played by Terry Crews.
The Longest Yard is a 2005 American sports comedy film directed
by Peter Segal and written by Sheldon Turner.
A remake of 1974's film of the same name, it stars Adam Sandler as a washed-up former professional American
football quarterback who goes to prison and is forced to assemble a team to play against the guards.
The film co-stars Chris Rock, James Cromwell, Nelly, William Fichtner, David Patrick Kelly, Tracy
Morgan, Cloris Leachman, and Burt Reynolds, who played Sandler's role in the original.
It was released by Paramount Pictures in the United States and Canada, and Sony Pictures Releasing–under the Columbia Pictures label–in other territories on
May 27, 2005, to negative reviews from critics, but the film was a box office success by grossing $191.2 million on an $82 million budget.
The film explores themes of prison, corruption,
prisoner, smuggling (contraband), sports.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.